on today's video we are going to make
banoffie pie ice cream in both the
ninja creami and in the traditional
ice cream machine and for banana ice
cream this one is actually going
to contain no Bananas at [Music]
all yeah I've made banana ice cream a couple of
times on the channel not that often it's not my
favorite flavor I don't mind it I actually just
don't like the texture of bananas it's a it's a
texture thing more than the taste but before we
get too deep into how need to just turn the oven
on to 350 F we're going to get these bananas in
there so banana ice cream Almost 100% of ice cream
scoop shops and companies out there do not use
bananas in their banana ice cream they use banana
extract and that is because bananas are bloody
expensive banana flavor actually comes from the
chem compound isoamyl acetate this is naturally
found in bananas but can easily be made within
a factory environment and if diluted actually
tastes more like pears than bananas itself and
by roasting the bananas it encourages the sugars
to come to the surface of the flesh which means
that we can actually draw the flavor out of the
banana itself it gives a deeper banana flavor
and allows some of that myod reaction to take
place which encourages additional flavor notes
you can just buy banana extract that's what
you want to do go for it you know no problems
whatsoever this is quite wasteful of bananas but
you do get a real banana taste and I'm not a huge
fan of that fake banana flavor maybe that's why
I don't really like banana ice cream but once
youd make it this way I think you're going to be
pleasantly surprised now we're not going to we're
literally going to do nothing to these apart from
put them on a baking sheet now these will in the
oven leak some of that sugar so you need to
make sure you line your pan with something
otherwise you're going to have a burnt sugar
layer on your baking sheet and that's really
not pleasant to get off so bananas on like
that as soon as gets up to temperature we're
going to put them in now a bit more
about bofi pie it's a it's a UK thing
it's it's spreading around the world uh I
don't think they have it here in Canada,
people do obviously know about it but banoffie
pie is a standard pie crust so a cookie pie
cruster graham cracker a digestive biscuit an
oat biscuit anything like that canopie crust
with the internet over here seems to say it's a
caramel base it's not it's specifically cheap ass
do deche the stuff you get in a can like this
that is what it is this is not this is a type
of caramel but it's not caramel those people in
South America would roll in their grave if you
just called this caramel on top of that is sliced
banana pieces then on top of that is some kind of
whipped cream and then you can decorate it with
you know people decorate it with shaved chocolate
or more banana or whatever that is a banoffie
pie banana toffee that's where the name comes
from so to start this we're going to weigh out
our ingredients get them in a pan and get them
cooking what you're going to need for the banana
ice cream base is 537g of milk I use 2% you can
use whatever milk you want 550g of cream at 33 3%
fat you absolutely can use full double cream you
can use 36% heavy cream it's fine 240g of sugar
25g of either corn syrup or golden syrup or Inver
sugar and 55g of skim milk powder in addition to
that you're going to need three bananas they're
kind of medium sized I guess 537g of milk 550g of
our whipping cream 240g of sugar going to take a
little container 10g of sugar in there so that's
actually 230g in there 10g in here uh today I'm
using special ingredients ice cream stabilizer,
use whatever stabilizer you have mix blend single
cold hot whatever doesn't make any difference
we're going to use 2g it's a little more than
tiny bit more than normal but for some reason
banana ice cream can go can feel really cold
in goes our stabilizer with that last little bit
of sugar and finally we have that so corn syrup
you can either use plain transparent corn syrup
you can use your golden corn syrup you can use
golden syrup it's it's doesn't really matter now
I personally prefer to use golden syrup or golden
corn syrup if I get the lid open 25g that golden
syrup corn syrup just adds this another element
of flavor to this banana ice cream finally
skin milk powder I'm using a teaspoon and it's
[Music]
55g of our skim milk powder right that's that now
if you can't tell the oven is
ready bananas are going to go
in they're not going in for long they're going
in for about 10 to 15 minutes and that is enough
to warm the banana flesh through to start the
mild reaction within the actual fruit itself
and to bring the sugars out to the surface along
with that banana flavor so now that we've got all
our ingredients in our pan let's just start
to mix this together you will as there's corn
syrup in here you will feel that as a lump at
the bottom of your whisk don't worry about it
it will melt the moment we put it on the heat so
let's do that on the hob as we're using a cook
stabilizer 85c 185f right now our ice cream base
is on there it's just gone on so I don't have to
worry about it for a few minutes and our bananas
are in the oven what we're going to do is look
at our Graham crumb base this is our pie crust
if you will we're going to take a small little
doad thank you Ika and we're going to add 200g
of graham cracker crumb you can use digestive
biscuits in the ukuk hobnobs works really well too
uh if you don't have hobnobs where you live then
in Canada anyway in Safeway you can buy these
and these are actually an excellent kind of
hobnob alternative they're a little bit harder um
a little bit smaller too but they've got a really
nice smell to them and they're not the same as
hnms but they're reasonably close tasty biscuits
cookies so get rid of that 200g of
our Graham crumb I also love Graham
crumb graham cracker and we need to add
some butter to that banana is steaming
Bananas full of water so don't stress if you
open your oven and there's steam coming out
80g of butter melt it in a microwave
our melted butter in here and finally
is some sugar and we are just going to
add 20g so that's 4 teaspoons little
spatula now if you want to know why we put the
sugar in here is as you cook this or as we cook
this in the oven that Sugar will melt and create
a much more cohesive mix that doesn't break up
into tiny little pieces in goes our butter you
can add a little bit more butter if you want
if you mix this together and you find it's
too dry for your liking add another 5 Gish
of butter doesn't really hurt all that will
happen is that as you bake it cuz you're not
baking this for long as you bake it that butter
will Bubble Up and will make the Surface look
very liquid very wet it's fine don't stress
about it because you're going to let it cool
and then we're going to cut it up and it will
solidify somewhat anyway during that stage so
what we're looking for is kind of that atypical
wet sand mix like that little bit of parchment
paper whoa made a mess there didn't I so put
that in a nice little pan whatever size you
got is fine doesn't really matter and then push
it down into the pan get it nicely compressed a
nice solid block that's what you want our oven
is on with our bananas I'm going to open it up
it's going to fill the kitchen with steam that is
okay and we're going to put this in for about 10
to 12 minutes at which point they'll both be
able to come out of the oven the bananas are
Browning now nicely just another 10 minutes or
so and they'll be good to go we want the Skins
basically black and that tells us that that
mild reaction is has come to a point that we
can taste the difference here so all I'm going to
going to do now is just continue to stir the ice
cream base until it comes up to temperature
and we'll get everything in for the next
stage right bananas are out we're going to
obviously I said I'd do this in a creamy but
we need to do the steeping stage first so that
will just sit there until this is ready into
our large bowl goes our ice cream base and
what we're going to do is is we are going to
take the bananas out of here and put them in
there we don't want the Skins so we're just
going for the flesh I will say these are hot
and the sugar has come out and if you've ever
burnt yourself with Hot Sugar you'll know
how painful that is so please be careful
our banana flesh is in here and we're going
to leave those in there overnight out comes
our graham cracker crumb doesn't take long to
burn this don't overcook this okay and then once
that's cooled down we're going to put it in the
refrigerator again overnight and then we've only
got one more stage to do so the next day the ice
cream base has come out of the fridge it's been
steeping for that entire time and we're going
to remove our banana flesh from our base they
usually stay together pretty well so you shouldn't
have much issues with doing that I've removed and
filled a ninja creamy tub already and the rest
is going in the machine for churning whilst it's
churning we're going to get our cookie crumb
base out of the fridge and chop that up into
to small suitable size pieces suitable size
that's up to you I normally chop them up to
about 1 cm 10 mm just shy of half an inch kind
of size I find that a really nice size for any
kind of ice cream mix these will be gloriously
buttery and melt in your mouth we're just going
to put them in a pot and look at this what is
called Dela deche Eagle brand canned delsa dele
this looks disgusting so before we do anything
let's taste it and yes it is disgusting so we're
not going to use that we're going to use actual
real DOA deetra that's come from South America as
you can see it's a very very different thing
the eagle brown one is basically burnt kind
of sugary caramel it's it's really not pleasant
whereas this Real doid Del is much thicker texture
beautiful taste it's going to go perfectly with
this but it's been in the fridge so I need to get
this loosened back up in the microwave so we're
going to spoon some into this little container
and we're going to melt it in the microwave now
cuz then it's got a good few minutes to cool
down before we load up our tubs much much better
smell consistency taste yeah this is this is the
stuff to use please don't use Eagle brand doid
Electro it's crap this is good so in the final
stages of churning we're going to start adding
in our little cubes of cookie crumb base now
that the churn is finished we're going to start
loading up our tub a spoonful of our ice cream
base followed by a spoonful of our Del leche
and then a few more pieces of our cookie crumb
base before loading up the tubs to completion
then we're going to pop them in the freezer to
completely harden off so now it's time for
the ninja creamy base this has come out of
freezer after being in there overnight and we're
going to spin this up you can see there's no lump
on there there's no ninja creamy hump as it's
known all my recipes work perfectly in your
Ninja creamy unlike the majority of recipes
out there we're going to get this spun up and
then we're going to look at dishing this
up so there we go ninja creamy and muzo
churned boffi pie ice cream so let's let's get
some dished up right let's do two spines this
is the traditional churned one with the do dee
and the cookie crumb inside delicious and this
is our ninja creamy with the cookie crumb and doo
DEET on the top again looks delicious so so there
we have it two different approaches to the same
ice cream obviously in the Ninja creamy if you
put this in the machine and run the addin it it's
literally just going to disintegrate into nothing
that's cuz it's so deliciously buttery same with
the do deetra it would just be decimated into
the ice cream obviously you've seen me Heat
this up just to um get it make it pourable
I'll come back to that I really wanted this one
to work back in the UK you can buy really quite
good doid lurcher I mean it's incredibly sweet
and it's nowhere near as good as actual proper
stuff but for a tin stuff it's it's really
good but this is really thin and tastes burnt
it reminds me of a caramel flavor that goes in
Starbucks drinks so people have been asking for
Starbucks frappuccino I'm going to keep this in
the fridge keep this covered and I will use this
in a Starbucks frappuccino recipe which one is
better this is obviously a much more traditionally
made yeah texture is
good it's perfect banana R cream that buttery
biscuit crumb in there delicious great
cracker flavor coming through the
do DEET caramel cutting through
that banana flavor and that banana
flavor is incredible by the way ninja
creamy it's
good it does like the Finesse of the churned
one and it's it's melting much much faster
um and that is the insulating factor of the air
that goes into ice cream when you have air overrun
in ice cream those little air bubbles remain
insulated within the ice cream base itself and
they stop or slow melting down when you don't have
any air in your ice cream and you get this super
fudgy once the temperature gets to the point where
it actually starts to melt it melts exponentially
fast so it would just melt incredibly quickly
once it starts to melt that's the that's just
one of the problems with a ninja creamy and a
packag jet too same thing um you know a lot of
people say is it is a ninja creamy better than a
packag jet they're basically the same thing but
you can see that this one is is melting really
really quickly doesn't matter tastes great super
smooth I mean super smooth I mean it's minus
6 outside right now it's let me um show you
outside [__] and we've got another I think we've
got another foot of snow coming today and tonight
so that that will equate to you know 18 in of snow
out there for this weekend perfect weather to be
sat down and and eating glorious banana ice
cream or banoffi pie ice cream it's just all
good perfect banana ice cream with graham crumb
pieces and doce deche otherwise known in the UK
as banofie pie thanks very much for watching don't
forget to like And subscribe I don't know what I'm
going to do next week I've um I've had so many
excellent suggestions but there's one that really
takes my fancy and it's not one I've ever done
before so if you want to see what that is and
let me know if you want me to do combo videos like
this ninja creamy and churn or whether you want
me to split it up in the comments don't forget
to like And subscribe see you next time [Music]